<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Cabral&#39;s architect portfolio squarespace issues</title>
    <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797</link>
    <description>[quote=&quot;Daniel Cabral&quot;]
Subject: Help with multiple issues on a Squarespace project

Message: First, a little context: the website is the portfolio for an
architect. It starts with a cover page that links to the portuguese and the
english version of the website. The english version is actually a second
squarespace project, identical to the first and pointing to a subdomain.

The issues I need to fix are the following:

COVER PAGE

- Logo on cover page is not centrally aligned on mobile. It is always a
little to the right, and depending on the screen size, a lot to the right.


SITE IN PORTUGUESE

- The site is not loading properly on mobile (smartphones or ipads). The
layout is rendered too different from what the template is supposed to look
like (http://flatiron-demo.squarespace.com/).

- on the page “projetos”, the name of each project is not showing up on top
of the picture, as it should do.

- On a project’s page, images should occupy the whole screen, but are
actually rather small and aligned to the right. In some smartphones, the
images simply don’t load.


SITE IN ENGLISH

- For some reason, it seems like on mobile devices, the website is not
loading the same visual template as the portuguese site.

- On a project’s page, images should occupy the whole screen, but are
actually rather small and aligned to the right. In some smartphones, the
images simply don’t load.

- The website is supposed to appear under the subdomain
“english.semerene.com”, but it is not working very well. If I click in any
link, even for another website, it keeps showing on the URL address the
same “english.semerene.com”. Try clicking on the logo, for example. It
leads you to the same page hosted on “semerene.com”, but the address bar
shows “english.semerene.com”.


INSTAGRAM BLOCK

- On page “diario visual” or “visual journal”: for some reason, there is a
“hole” on the grid of instagram images.
[/quote]

&lt;small&gt;&quot;post can&#39;t be empty&quot; due to discourse bug. message to be removed&lt;/small&gt;</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 14:07:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Daniel Cabral&#39;s architect portfolio squarespace issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://talk.cregox.com/u/cregox">@cregox</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Dear Daniel, </p>

<p>It just so happen I'm in between jobs right now or else I would simply say I couldn't take this gig. Also I don't do this kind of work since June past year for many reasons I've already talked about.</p>

<p>So, before I even try to analyze anything here I want to ask you:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Have you read <a href="http://www.cregox.com/your-home">the (discontinued) "your home" page</a>?</p></li>
<li><p>Given the number of issues alone, this will be at least a 1 day project, at U$984. Should we proceed talking business?</p></li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 14:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-7797-2</guid>
        <source url="http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797.rss">Daniel Cabral&#39;s architect portfolio squarespace issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Daniel Cabral&#39;s architect portfolio squarespace issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@system system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://talk.cregox.com/u/system">@system</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>Daniel Cabral:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Subject: Help with multiple issues on a Squarespace project</p>
<p>Message: First, a little context: the website is the portfolio for an<br>architect. It starts with a cover page that links to the portuguese and the<br>english version of the website. The english version is actually a second<br>squarespace project, identical to the first and pointing to a subdomain.</p>
<p>The issues I need to fix are the following:</p>
<p>COVER PAGE</p>
<p>- Logo on cover page is not centrally aligned on mobile. It is always a<br>little to the right, and depending on the screen size, a lot to the right.</p>
<p>SITE IN PORTUGUESE</p>
<p>- The site is not loading properly on mobile (smartphones or ipads). The<br>layout is rendered too different from what the template is supposed to look<br>like (http://flatiron-demo.squarespace.com/).</p>
<p>- on the page “projetos”, the name of each project is not showing up on top<br>of the picture, as it should do.</p>
<p>- On a project’s page, images should occupy the whole screen, but are<br>actually rather small and aligned to the right. In some smartphones, the<br>images simply don’t load.</p>
<p>SITE IN ENGLISH</p>
<p>- For some reason, it seems like on mobile devices, the website is not<br>loading the same visual template as the portuguese site.</p>
<p>- On a project’s page, images should occupy the whole screen, but are<br>actually rather small and aligned to the right. In some smartphones, the<br>images simply don’t load.</p>
<p>- The website is supposed to appear under the subdomain<br>“english.semerene.com”, but it is not working very well. If I click in any<br>link, even for another website, it keeps showing on the URL address the<br>same “english.semerene.com”. Try clicking on the logo, for example. It<br>leads you to the same page hosted on “semerene.com”, but the address bar<br>shows “english.semerene.com”.</p>
<p>INSTAGRAM BLOCK</p>
<p>- On page “diario visual” or “visual journal”: for some reason, there is a<br>“hole” on the grid of instagram images.</p>
</blockquote></aside>

<p><small>"post can't be empty" due to discourse bug. message to be removed</small></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-7797-1</guid>
        <source url="http://talk.cregox.com/t/daniel-cabrals-architect-portfolio-squarespace-issues/7797.rss">Daniel Cabral&#39;s architect portfolio squarespace issues</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
