<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>E-commerce on Squarespace</title>
    <link>/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459</link>
    <description>[quote=&quot;safi.tvb@youngandboldafrican.com&quot;]
Hello,

I have a website with Squarespace and I&#39;m planning to launch my first
clothes collection end of May - beginning of June. My clothes will be sold
on my website. I plan to let a fulfilment company handles the shipment of
my orders to customers, however I have some issues with the Squarespace
integrated e-commerce. Most fulfilment companies need to integrate an
external API which is not possible with the actual integrated Squarespace
e-commerce.
I&#39;m looking for someone capable to create an user friendly e-commerce and
allowing me to make the changes by myself in the future.
Could I have a quote please?

 Kind regards, 
[/quote]</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 17:19:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>closing</category>
    <atom:link href="/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>E-commerce on Squarespace</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/talk/u/cregox">@cregox</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I'm not sure if you have but please, read this first:
<a href="http://www.cregox.com/your-home">www.cregox.com/your-home</a></p>

<p>I don't think squarespace ever had or will have an API. Or any way to get
data in (the server side). We can only work with content and client side
scripts. Even the "developer" platform is only meant to develop templates
(all client side).</p>

<p>That being said, it looks like shipstation, for instance, does offer
squarespace integration. <a href="http://www.shipstation.com/">http://www.shipstation.com/</a> It's not impossible to
think how that works, they have their own servers and you need an account
there. The only thing that will never happen this way is an integration
between their commerce and squarespace's, for stock control and all that
stuff.</p>

<p>I could work something out for you, but I can't give a good estimate on
final quote. What I can do is tell you to get something working (using
something like shipstation) which I myself would be glad to work with, it
will be less than U$432. Then we can move from there if you need more.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 17:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-7459-4</guid>
        <source url="/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459.rss">E-commerce on Squarespace</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>E-commerce on Squarespace</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@system system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/talk/u/system">@system</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>safi.tvb@youngandboldafrican.com:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Hello,</p>
<p>I have a website with Squarespace and I'm planning to launch my first<br>clothes collection end of May - beginning of June. My clothes will be sold<br>on my website. I plan to let a fulfilment company handles the shipment of<br>my orders to customers, however I have some issues with the Squarespace<br>integrated e-commerce. Most fulfilment companies need to integrate an<br>external API which is not possible with the actual integrated Squarespace<br>e-commerce.<br>I'm looking for someone capable to create an user friendly e-commerce and<br>allowing me to make the changes by myself in the future.<br>Could I have a quote please?</p>
<p> Kind regards, </p>
</blockquote></aside>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 15:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-7459-1</guid>
        <source url="/talk/t/e-commerce-on-squarespace/7459.rss">E-commerce on Squarespace</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
