<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>[spoilers] How big was the big bang?</title>
    <link>/talk/t/spoilers-how-big-was-the-big-bang/7761</link>
    <description>I was going to ask a question very similar to [Can light affect gravity](http://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/121259/can-light-affect-gravity) but not based in any theory, just trying to better understand General Relativity in my own way. Then, when I started writing and elaborating more about it, I noticed the kernel of my question might actually be about the big bang... Now, back to the beginning:

&gt; According to special relativity, *C* is the maximum speed at which all matter and information in the universe can travel.

This still rubs me in the wrong way. Like the space time continuum, a 4 dimensional comprised of 3 spaces and 1 in time, doesn&#39;t seen right, but that&#39;s to another topic...

So, after watching this ***awesome** 7 minute video* explaining it in &quot;very simple&quot; terms, I went to (had to go) researching more about General Relativity and stuff:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CYv5GsXEf1o

While watching the video I was just reafirming my previous knowledge up to the precise 5:00 point, when he says &quot;speed of light is constant, **as long as** you&#39;re measuring it from a reference frame that&#39;s moving at a constant velocity&quot;. I now realize that&#39;s a bit far from being very precise, but it was also bringing to me a new idea. It&#39;s not what I understood of the *C* light Constant.

To me, light speed was *universally always constant*, regardless of the reference frame! Which was mind blowing and made little sense, when I wrapped my head around it a bit. Now it&#39;s back to make no sense, and I&#39;m glad it was a wrong picture I&#39;ve made!

In reality, [I now understand](http://physics.stackexchange.com/a/2290/70637) it still moves at that constant speed, relatively to anything else, **but** always dependant on the fabric of spacetime it&#39;s immersed into. This can easily accounts to what Ryan Chester genius kid meant in his sentence there (and to what truly can be observed).

Light will still be moving *C* faster than any &quot;*stationary*&quot; object, in vacuum, if both are under &quot;*the same roof*&quot; and even if that &quot;*roof*&quot; is moving at 99.99999...% the *C* speed of light.

But what does `moving at` even mean, in that case, if every movement is relative? There always seem to be some kind of absolute reference implicit in every speech I hear or read. Is that absolute frame the big bang? I guess so! No idea, really.

Anyway, in the end, this is still all just some random thoughts, I guess. Should mark it as `open draft` (a.k.a. `spoilers` category, around here) and move on for now.

Here are some more thoughts:

- A huge body of mass affects the space time continuum, through gravity waves moving at *C*, where a lot of energy is somehow used `E = M * C ^2`
- Light (and other particles) move so fast and have so little mass that they can&#39;t be easily affected by the space time - only huge amounts of energy can bend space time enough to interfere with light.
- http://physics.stackexchange.com/a/7457/70637</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 03:01:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>chaotic science</category>
    <atom:link href="/talk/t/spoilers-how-big-was-the-big-bang/7761.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>[spoilers] How big was the big bang?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/talk/u/cregox">@cregox</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was going to ask a question very similar to <a href="http://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/121259/can-light-affect-gravity">Can light affect gravity</a> but not based in any theory, just trying to better understand General Relativity in my own way. Then, when I started writing and elaborating more about it, I noticed the kernel of my question might actually be about the big bang... Now, back to the beginning:</p>

<blockquote><p>According to special relativity, <em>C</em> is the maximum speed at which all matter and information in the universe can travel.</p></blockquote>

<p>This still rubs me in the wrong way. Like the space time continuum, a 4 dimensional comprised of 3 spaces and 1 in time, doesn't seen right, but that's to another topic...</p>

<p>So, after watching this <em><strong>awesome</strong> 7 minute video</em> explaining it in "very simple" terms, I went to (had to go) researching more about General Relativity and stuff:</p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="CYv5GsXEf1o" data-youtube-title="Breakthrough Junior Challenge: Some Cool Ways of Looking at the Special Theory of Relativity" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>

<p>While watching the video I was just reafirming my previous knowledge up to the precise 5:00 point, when he says "speed of light is constant, <strong>as long as</strong> you're measuring it from a reference frame that's moving at a constant velocity". I now realize that's a bit far from being very precise, but it was also bringing to me a new idea. It's not what I understood of the <em>C</em> light Constant.</p>

<p>To me, light speed was <em>universally always constant</em>, regardless of the reference frame! Which was mind blowing and made little sense, when I wrapped my head around it a bit. Now it's back to make no sense, and I'm glad it was a wrong picture I've made!</p>

<p>In reality, <a href="http://physics.stackexchange.com/a/2290/70637">I now understand</a> it still moves at that constant speed, relatively to anything else, <strong>but</strong> always dependant on the fabric of spacetime it's immersed into. This can easily accounts to what Ryan Chester genius kid meant in his sentence there (and to what truly can be observed).</p>

<p>Light will still be moving <em>C</em> faster than any "<em>stationary</em>" object, in vacuum, if both are under "<em>the same roof</em>" and even if that "<em>roof</em>" is moving at 99.99999...% the <em>C</em> speed of light.</p>

<p>But what does <code>moving at</code> even mean, in that case, if every movement is relative? There always seem to be some kind of absolute reference implicit in every speech I hear or read. Is that absolute frame the big bang? I guess so! No idea, really.</p>

<p>Anyway, in the end, this is still all just some random thoughts, I guess. Should mark it as <code>open draft</code> (a.k.a. <code>spoilers</code> category, around here) and move on for now.</p>

<p>Here are some more thoughts:</p>

<ul>
<li>A huge body of mass affects the space time continuum, through gravity waves moving at <em>C</em>, where a lot of energy is somehow used <code>E = M * C ^2</code>
</li>
<li>Light (and other particles) move so fast and have so little mass that they can't be easily affected by the space time - only huge amounts of energy can bend space time enough to interfere with light.</li>
<li><a href="http://physics.stackexchange.com/a/7457/70637">http://physics.stackexchange.com/a/7457/70637</a></li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="/talk/t/spoilers-how-big-was-the-big-bang/7761/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>/talk/t/spoilers-how-big-was-the-big-bang/7761/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 03:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-7761-1</guid>
        <source url="/talk/t/spoilers-how-big-was-the-big-bang/7761.rss">[spoilers] How big was the big bang?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
