<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to cregox talk</title>
    <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/welcome-to-cregox-talk/6</link>
    <description>cregox talk is a random forum-ish place where we can talk about anything! *We shall never delete or moderate a post that isn&#39;t considered clear spam.*

# **Who is it for?**

Anyone interested in chaos!

There are 3 commandments of what should be avoided at all costs (never forbidden). These are among the most circular and vicious popular subjects in the world today (and for the longest time):

no religion
no politics
no possessions &lt;small&gt;(under [review](http://talk.cregox.com/t/lets-make-a-podcast/7753) of a better short term for the general idea)&lt;/small&gt;

## **What can you find here?**

A lot of confusing texts, mostly around [categories on buffer](http://talk.cregox.com/c/buffer), probably still such as: tech, science, skepticism, philosophy, entertainment, porn, intelligence and some meta. You know, anything that matters! :D

# **Why should you come here?**

Because [you could not find anywhere else good enough][2]! There are many communities out there, but they&#39;re either too restrictive (I ended up finding up that even &quot;the daily wtf&quot; is [too restrictive to my taste](https://what.thedailywtf.com/topic/21279/unofficial-w-e-tldr-stuff-thread-spoilers-still-needed-nsfw/13)) and/or got a bad forums software.

In fact, if you do know of anywhere else, please let us know! We&#39;d love to go there. Just keep in mind the tool has to be at least as good as [nodeBB](https://nodebb.org/), [flarum](http://flarum.org/) or even the one we&#39;re still using here, as legacy, [discourse.org](http://discourse.org) (beware [Jeff is an ass](http://blog.cregox.com/2015/12/25/new-blog-platform-once-again.html)).

# **Where can you read more (links, resources, etc)?**

The [forum][4] was born from a fan (@cregox) of [SGU][5] who was too excited about using the most advanced forums tool there was back then and wanted to use it for free expression of anything in their mind.

## **Why you talk so much about that discourse thing?**

Think of [quora][6] and [reddit][7], if you will, but using this open source technology made by the same guys from [StackOverflow][8]. You&#39;ll *probably* only be able to understand how good this is once you start using it, and once we do have a community to power it up. So, do try out [some similar sites with bigger communities (these are their paying customers)](https://www.discourse.org/faq/customers). But **don&#39;t go too far into building a huge community**, or [you could easily break the toy](https://what.thedailywtf.com/t/tdwtf-forum-faq/370).


  [1]: http://www.discourse.org
  [2]: http://talk.cregox.com/t/similar-web-sites-forums/52/1
  [3]: http://blog.codinghorror.com/
  [4]: http://talk.cregox.com/t/a-beginning-for-the-forums-here/7?u=cawas
  [5]: http://www.theskepticsguide.org/
  [6]: http://www.quora.com
  [7]: http://www.reddit.com
  [8]: http://www.stackexchange.com
  [9]: http://bbs.boingboing.net/
  [10]: http://discuss.howtogeek.com/
  [11]: http://discourse.codinghorror.com/</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 14:48:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>meta</category>
    <atom:link href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/welcome-to-cregox-talk/6.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to cregox talk</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@system system]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://talk.cregox.com/u/system">@system</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>cregox talk is a random forum-ish place where we can talk about anything! <em>We shall never delete or moderate a post that isn't considered clear spam.</em></p>

<h1><strong>Who is it for?</strong></h1>

<p>Anyone interested in chaos!</p>

<p>There are 3 commandments of what should be avoided at all costs (never forbidden). These are among the most circular and vicious popular subjects in the world today (and for the longest time):</p>

<p>no religion<br>no politics<br>no possessions <small>(under <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/lets-make-a-podcast/7753">review</a> of a better short term for the general idea)</small></p>

<h2><strong>What can you find here?</strong></h2>

<p>A lot of confusing texts, mostly around <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/c/buffer">categories on buffer</a>, probably still such as: tech, science, skepticism, philosophy, entertainment, porn, intelligence and some meta. You know, anything that matters! <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/smiley.png?v=3" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>

<h1><strong>Why should you come here?</strong></h1>

<p>Because <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/similar-web-sites-forums/52/1">you could not find anywhere else good enough</a>! There are many communities out there, but they're either too restrictive (I ended up finding up that even "the daily wtf" is <a href="https://what.thedailywtf.com/topic/21279/unofficial-w-e-tldr-stuff-thread-spoilers-still-needed-nsfw/13">too restrictive to my taste</a>) and/or got a bad forums software.</p>

<p>In fact, if you do know of anywhere else, please let us know! We'd love to go there. Just keep in mind the tool has to be at least as good as <a href="https://nodebb.org/">nodeBB</a>, <a href="http://flarum.org/">flarum</a> or even the one we're still using here, as legacy, <a href="http://discourse.org">discourse.org</a> (beware <a href="http://blog.cregox.com/2015/12/25/new-blog-platform-once-again.html">Jeff is an ass</a>).</p>

<h1><strong>Where can you read more (links, resources, etc)?</strong></h1>

<p>The <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/a-beginning-for-the-forums-here/7?u=cawas">forum</a> was born from a fan (<a class="mention" href="/users/cregox">@cregox</a>) of <a href="http://www.theskepticsguide.org/">SGU</a> who was too excited about using the most advanced forums tool there was back then and wanted to use it for free expression of anything in their mind.</p>

<h2><strong>Why you talk so much about that discourse thing?</strong></h2>

<p>Think of <a href="http://www.quora.com">quora</a> and <a href="http://www.reddit.com">reddit</a>, if you will, but using this open source technology made by the same guys from <a href="http://www.stackexchange.com">StackOverflow</a>. You'll <em>probably</em> only be able to understand how good this is once you start using it, and once we do have a community to power it up. So, do try out <a href="https://www.discourse.org/faq/customers">some similar sites with bigger communities (these are their paying customers)</a>. But <strong>don't go too far into building a huge community</strong>, or <a href="https://what.thedailywtf.com/t/tdwtf-forum-faq/370">you could easily break the toy</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/welcome-to-cregox-talk/6/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/welcome-to-cregox-talk/6/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-6-1</guid>
        <source url="http://talk.cregox.com/t/welcome-to-cregox-talk/6.rss">Welcome to cregox talk</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
