<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>cregox talk - Latest posts</title>
    <link>http://talk.cregox.com</link>
    <description>Latest posts</description>
      <item>
        <title>Shut down announcement</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/shut-down-announcement/7945/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 08:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8819</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Shut down announcement</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/shut-down-announcement/7945/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 08:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8818</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Shut down announcement</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/shut-down-announcement/7945/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 08:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8817</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Shut down announcement</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/shut-down-announcement/7945/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 08:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8816</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Shut down announcement</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>this host will shut down soon, probably before July!</p>

<p><a href="http://explosm.net/comics/1135/"><img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/uploads/default/original/1X/abd89729faa2d0b45fc8037fe0e711fb8baca471.png" alt='googled for "pull the plug" animated images, found it thanks to link from &lt;a href="http://www.funnyjunk.com/funny_pictures/89591/Pull#69470a_159660"&gt;http://www.funnyjunk.com/funny_pictures/89591/Pull#69470a_159660&lt;/a&gt; and went for full credit' width="489" height="396"></a><br><small><em>don't freak out!</em></small></p>

<p>I've actually announced this "trend" a while ago <a href="http://blog.cregox.com/medium-new-blog-announcement-eYdVBD2">elsewhere</a>.</p>

<p>got an awesome digital ocean support feedback from an email I wrote them about this situation. basically, they cheered me up, told me to hang in there, <strong>and gave me U$40 of credit</strong> <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/smiley.png?v=3" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"> so I could have enough time to figure out what to do. I decided to go with little to no work...</p>

<p>basically I'll manually <a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/print-long-topic-to-pdf-redux-again/44639/45?u=cregox">print</a> some relevant topics and host it somewhere. I'll keep full backups of the whole talk, and it should be easy to bring it back up in the next few years, if anyone wishes to. and until the last day here (see below) I'll try to do some scripting for exporting as much content as possible.</p>

<p>at some point I may want to <a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/freezing-discourse-site/23225/2?u=cregox">freeze</a> the whole site and not allow any new posts, just to keep the last backup consistent.</p>

<p>not sure when exactly the plug will be pulled though, it will be for whichever comes first: I finish exporting or the current credit is over. right now I've got $37.40 and a $12 bill per month so current date estimations point to July 6th as the last day.</p>

<p>finally, for further reference, always go to the main domain: <a href="https://cregox.com">https://cregox.com</a> or google. <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=3" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/shut-down-announcement/7945/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 08:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8815</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A feedback for my application at crossover</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seyfer Oleg Abrazhaev]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I'm fully agree with your opinion about application process. TopTal has almost the same, but they are use Codility and test only algorithm problems.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/a-feedback-for-my-application-at-crossover/7658/51</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 10:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8800</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A beginning for the forums here</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="7"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/user_avatar/talk.cregox.com/cregox/40/60_1.png" class="avatar">cregox:</div>
<blockquote><p>This is the origin of this "forum".</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>The link there was to a post now lost (<a href="http://sguforums.com/index.php/topic,43130.msg9293656.html#msg9293656">the folks there lost all the data</a>), in which I was literally illuded.</p>

<p>Today the forum is still a "ghost town" since I'm still the only somewhat active <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/users?period=all">user</a> around. <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/frowning.png?v=3" title=":frowning:" class="emoji" alt=":frowning:"></p>

<p>And I'm keeping it up at a huge hosting cost... Needing to move this to a free solution (since now I also got a will to <a href="http://blog.cregox.com/2015/12/25/new-blog-platform-once-again.html">move away from discourse</a>, although I shall continue living with it if I can find a free host and easy way to move). I'd ask here "any hints anyone?" but ghosts won't answer! <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/smiley.png?v=3" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/a-beginning-for-the-forums-here/7/7</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 10:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8795</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Focus on mario, forget the rest of universe</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>wow, this is being a long hiatus!<br>probably it will still stay like <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/a-s-i-or-job-hunting/7717/2">this</a> for a while. <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/cry.png?v=3" title=":cry:" class="emoji" alt=":cry:"> </p>

<p>anyway, back to topic.</p>

<p><video width="100%" height="100%" controls><source src="https://openai-sci-demonstrations.s3.amazonaws.com/site-assets/karpathy/flashgames_6x11.mp4"><a href="https://openai-sci-demonstrations.s3.amazonaws.com/site-assets/karpathy/flashgames_6x11.mp4">https://openai-sci-demonstrations.s3.amazonaws.com/site-assets/karpathy/flashgames_6x11.mp4</a></source></video><br><em>a sample of Universe game environments played by human demonstrators.</em></p>

<p>one day before openai newest release <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/to-kstanley-can-a-neat-mario-start-up-a-basiux/7914/5?u=cregox">I was officially starting to try getting basiux back up</a>. I saw the news and left it on my "read later" list. then, a few hours after replying to mr Stanley there, I finally got to see what <a href="https://universe.openai.com/">openai universe</a> was all about. and...</p>

<p>yet again, they have a lot of similar aspects from what I want to do / see being done. it surprised me, as I wasn't expecting they would continue on going through such a related route at all. plus, the work there is <strong>amazing</strong>!</p>

<p>still, and yet again (again), it doesn't come without its flaws, at least the way I see.</p>

<p>the main issue might also be their biggest win: it's not easy enough to contribute. you do need to install docker, universe and at least toy with python to get in the boat. of course this easily can prove to be beneficial for their goals or even for basiux as a whole, but I'm pretty positive this is a bad choice for bringing it as soon as possible.</p>

<p>making it so generic and, at the same time, focusing on game learning, doesn't rub me in a good way as well. it's a great plan for helping us in figuring out better algorithms, which we still need to do. but not so much for improving a good algorithm or making it grow in the most beneficial way. for all we currently know today, we might already have good enough algorithms and they'd just be lacking a proper tweak along with combined hardware power. if we limit its inputs to keyboard and pixels from games, probably no algorithm today would have enough resources to raise up as a basiux.</p>

<p>and what does all this means to us?</p>

<p>I guess not much.</p>

<p>we still gotta build something to showcase basiux's value. maybe it can now incorporate this universe, maybe it can't, doesn't really matter. if we can't easily use it, it'll probably be better to stick with the plan for now: make a hyper neat mariox so anyone can play with it and effortlessly "share Ai benchmarks for transfer learning" (as they put it).</p>

<p>in another hand, if you want to better understand basiux current efforts, well, now we can simply say:</p>

<blockquote><p>we want to build a kind of openai universe for any user, focused on making it fun and social</p></blockquote>

<p>controversially, if this helps us explaining our plan, in itself is already quite a lot! (in opposite to "not much")</p>

<p>also, maybe <a href="http://discuss.openai.com/">their forums</a> (also using discourse - regardless of <a href="http://blog.cregox.com/2015/12/25/new-blog-platform-once-again.html">how "terrible"</a> it is, <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/welcome-to-cregox-talk/6/1">we're still using it</a> too) can bring us much value as well.</p>

<p>as for the <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/true-randomness-app-why-it-could-help-winning-the-lottery-and-building-up-the-basiux/7845?u=cregox">latest plan about randomness</a>, well, it's obviously too bold of a bet for this stage. hopefully later, supposing it eventually pins out. <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>

<p><small>ps: read <a href="http://talk.cregox.com/t/yeah-im-also-a-progammer/7676">this manifesto</a> if you're wondering what happened with my grammar.</small></p> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/focus-on-mario-forget-the-rest-of-universe/7919/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 14:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8787</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What is Artificial Intelligence (AI)?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>by the way, most times I forget to give proper props to people. sorry. <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/frowning.png?v=3" title=":frowning:" class="emoji" alt=":frowning:"></p>

<p><strong>welcome</strong> <a class="mention" href="/users/karthikaqpt">@KarthikaQpt</a> and <strong>thank you</strong> for being the only one forum contributor this year (other than myself) to create an Ai topic. <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>

<p>ps: you might find it a bit interesting to realize my question there (which I asked because you've requested) is still in need of a good answer.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/what-is-artificial-intelligence-ai/7881/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 11:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8786</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To kstanley: can a neat mario start up a basiux?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>those are good insights. thank you! <img src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>

<p>maybe one of the main points I'm actually trying to evolve here is eventually getting more people interested in doing things like mariox.</p>

<p>just posted <a href="https://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/neat/conversations/messages/6703">a random-ish message there</a>. here's a quote:</p>

<blockquote><p>I'd like to get this (mariox) to a point where people want to play with it like a tamagotchi and, with that, we could have a huge network of Ai trainers/players for multiple experiments and faster development of algorithms!</p></blockquote> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/to-kstanley-can-a-neat-mario-start-up-a-basiux/7914/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 12:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8785</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To kstanley: can a neat mario start up a basiux?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@kstanley kstanley]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="7914"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://talk-cdn.cregox.com/user_avatar/talk.cregox.com/cregox/40/60_1.png" class="avatar">cregox:</div>
<blockquote><p>Caue</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Hi Caue, I liked your javascript NEAT demo in Mario - very nice!  To answer your questions:</p>

<p>Knowing how far we are from the singularity is about knowing what we don't know.  People often are comfortable with knowing what we DO know, but it can be difficult to comprehend what we don't know.  Yet if you gain sufficient experience in a field like AI, you do come to some level of appreciation for what is unknown.  And in the case of intelligence, it's clear at present that the unknown is vast.  What we know right now is likely a tiny sliver of everything we hope to understand.  And when there are many things you don't know, you are looking at a situation where it could take decades for enough brilliant people to aggregate the ideas that it would take to really break through.</p>

<p>People have indeed looked at the rule of randomness in stochastic algorithms, though I am not an expert on it.  You can find some work on this topic through Google.  That said, the question of what is "true" random is pretty complicated and the bigger question is why it matters?  Is only true random sufficient fuel for exploration?  I don't know of a reason that has to be the case.</p>

<p>Regarding more people to talk to, you could join the NEAT Users Group at <a href="https://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/neat/info" rel="nofollow">https://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/neat/info</a></p>

<p>And thanks for the bug reports!</p>

<p>Best,</p>

<p>ken</p>

<p>Thanks for the bug reports.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>http://talk.cregox.com/t/to-kstanley-can-a-neat-mario-start-up-a-basiux/7914/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 08:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-8784</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
