<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Telling my story</title>
    <link>/talk/t/telling-my-story/417</link>
    <description>There&#39;s too [much to read](//cregox.com/blog) and too little to show, [about me][1]. Just try and [google me](//google.com/?q=%22caue+rego%22). Or go through each link there, on my [about][1], recursively.

Here I want to try and really start changing that. I feel like I&#39;ve got so much to tell... And I need to make myself clear somehow. Words just don&#39;t cut it.

Introduce [food seekers](//cregox.com/foodseekers).

Because we&#39;re still missing the next thing in communication-entertainment-technology and, while this won&#39;t be it, it&#39;s my current attempt to getting a first step in that direction.

  [1]: //cregox.com/about</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 22:22:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>food seekers</category>
    <atom:link href="/talk/t/telling-my-story/417.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Telling my story</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/talk/u/cregox">@cregox</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Few days ago I decided even this food seeker idea is too much for a next step.</p>

<p>So now I'm thinking about building either <a href="http://scratch.mit.edu/projects/17273607/">some kind of simple game</a> (or maybe some kind of <a href="http://cregox.com/esfi">esfi</a>) and/or an introductory video seeking for investment, like <a href="http://googlepleasehire.me/">that guy who did it for google</a>.</p>

<p>You see, I could use a good scholarship and I'm on the latest age I could get one. Instead of going to college with that money it, though, I'd spend it on expenses to focus in one thing only: get my project done (food seekers). 4 years will sure be enough. I could, in fact, get something done in the first year, now I know what it is. I actually have written a very simple script for a simpler idea yet.</p>

<p>I'd go to the best schools I could get free access to, anywhere in the world, and meet with people who are willing to join in and make it happen. I'd go to conventions and centers where I can meet those young people of any age, such as myself. I could do it alone in the first couple years, worst case scenario.</p>

<p>And I would make it happen. Just like I did with other <a href="http://www.cregox.com/projects/">achievable projects</a>.</p>

<p>But, I realize even if I do make a great video I still may find nobody willing to bet on me. Reason why I thought of just making "some simple game" and profiting from it. This, however, is something I might not be able to do within the few short months left I got in front of me...</p>

<p>And there I go, keep on trying to move forward! <img src="/talk/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=0" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt="wink" width="20" height="20"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="/talk/t/telling-my-story/417/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>/talk/t/telling-my-story/417/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 22:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-417-2</guid>
        <source url="/talk/t/telling-my-story/417.rss">Telling my story</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Telling my story</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/talk/u/cregox">@cregox</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There's too <a href="//cregox.com/blog">much to read</a> and too little to show, <a href="//cregox.com/about">about me</a>. Just try and <a href="//google.com/?q=%22caue+rego%22">google me</a>. Or go through each link there, on my <a href="//cregox.com/about">about</a>, recursively.</p>

<p>Here I want to try and really start changing that. I feel like I've got so much to tell... And I need to make myself clear somehow. Words just don't cut it.</p>

<p>Introduce <a href="//cregox.com/foodseekers">food seekers</a>.</p>

<p>Because we're still missing the next thing in communication-entertainment-technology and, while this won't be it, it's my current attempt to getting a first step in that direction.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="/talk/t/telling-my-story/417/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>/talk/t/telling-my-story/417/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 09:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-417-1</guid>
        <source url="/talk/t/telling-my-story/417.rss">Telling my story</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
