<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Quickmvp and digital marketing</title>
    <link>/talk/t/quickmvp-and-digital-marketing/7596</link>
    <description>&lt;small&gt;Disclaimer: the following was originally a message to Mr [Laurent][1], who never really replied back. So I decided to keep editing it to use it as a briefing (almost like [I did before][2]).&lt;/small&gt;

---

I was [talking with someone](/talk/t/insurance-angels-and-entrepreneurship/7593) and one of his advices were [producthunt](http://www.producthunt.com/) - there I found about [startupstash](http://startupstash.com/) which led me to [quickmvp](http://quickmvp.com/) - then when creating an account I noticed they take coupons and it&#39;s costumary I google for coupons before moving forward. And that&#39;s my short story on how I found [your article][3], Mr [Laurent][4].

Questions:

1. I wanted to do a quickmvp for [my next project][5], but while I&#39;m pretty sure there&#39;s a market for it I&#39;m now not so sure it&#39;s worth doing that right now. As good as such a validation might be, and that looks like an awesome &quot;cheap&quot; way to do it, somehow I feel like it&#39;s not a good enough next step. Supposing it goes well, I don&#39;t see what I could do after that to move it forward! Do you have any advice for this?

2. Also, I do have a kind of [my own startup already working][6]. And I understand me getting in touch with you asking for help have a cost for you. So, how can we make this work for you? Or even more, how do you make this work for you? I know some people just take the first contact costs built in anything else, and I bet that&#39;s how you do it as well. It&#39;s how I&#39;m trying to do.

3. But my company isn&#39;t doing well. And I think I need much marketing advise. I suppose maybe a &quot;digital marketing&quot; service, even. Is this something you can work on? I&#39;ve consulted a few marketing companies, but none so far in english (as I wouldn&#39;t know where to begin) and none so far who could take this job.

4. I could pay you any value to begin an assessment if you can give me guarantee of satisfaction. I just need to see results. If I&#39;m paid to make you a website or a tweak, you&#39;ll get the website or tweak you want, because I, as the professional here, know better than you what you really need or want. I guarantee you that. Granted, marketing isn&#39;t all that straight forward, but you need to tell me what results you can guarantee me, and I&#39;ll see if I want to take the risk. If that&#39;s worth it to try and get my sales up. So, what&#39;s your guarantee?


  [1]: https://www.sohelpful.me/laurentroger
  [2]: http://www.cregox.com/design-brief
  [3]: https://medium.com/@lc3t35/how-to-get-800-unique-visitors-in-3-weeks-with-quickmvp-com-c6e19ed5e1e4
  [4]: https://www.sohelpful.me/laurentroger
  [5]: http://cregox.com/advisor
  [6]: /talk/t/the-making-of-your-home/7491</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 18:14:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>public emails</category>
    <atom:link href="/talk/t/quickmvp-and-digital-marketing/7596.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Quickmvp and digital marketing</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@cregox Caue Rego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/talk/u/cregox">@cregox</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><small>Disclaimer: the following was originally a message to Mr <a href="https://www.sohelpful.me/laurentroger">Laurent</a>, who never really replied back. So I decided to keep editing it to use it as a briefing (almost like <a href="http://www.cregox.com/design-brief">I did before</a>).</small></p>

<hr>

<p>I was <a href="/talk/t/insurance-angels-and-entrepreneurship/7593">talking with someone</a> and one of his advices were <a href="http://www.producthunt.com/">producthunt</a> - there I found about <a href="http://startupstash.com/">startupstash</a> which led me to <a href="http://quickmvp.com/">quickmvp</a> - then when creating an account I noticed they take coupons and it's costumary I google for coupons before moving forward. And that's my short story on how I found <a href="https://medium.com/@lc3t35/how-to-get-800-unique-visitors-in-3-weeks-with-quickmvp-com-c6e19ed5e1e4">your article</a>, Mr <a href="https://www.sohelpful.me/laurentroger">Laurent</a>.</p>

<p>Questions:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>I wanted to do a quickmvp for <a href="http://cregox.com/advisor">my next project</a>, but while I'm pretty sure there's a market for it I'm now not so sure it's worth doing that right now. As good as such a validation might be, and that looks like an awesome "cheap" way to do it, somehow I feel like it's not a good enough next step. Supposing it goes well, I don't see what I could do after that to move it forward! Do you have any advice for this?</p></li>
<li><p>Also, I do have a kind of <a href="/talk/t/the-making-of-your-home/7491">my own startup already working</a>. And I understand me getting in touch with you asking for help have a cost for you. So, how can we make this work for you? Or even more, how do you make this work for you? I know some people just take the first contact costs built in anything else, and I bet that's how you do it as well. It's how I'm trying to do.</p></li>
<li><p>But my company isn't doing well. And I think I need much marketing advise. I suppose maybe a "digital marketing" service, even. Is this something you can work on? I've consulted a few marketing companies, but none so far in english (as I wouldn't know where to begin) and none so far who could take this job.</p></li>
<li><p>I could pay you any value to begin an assessment if you can give me guarantee of satisfaction. I just need to see results. If I'm paid to make you a website or a tweak, you'll get the website or tweak you want, because I, as the professional here, know better than you what you really need or want. I guarantee you that. Granted, marketing isn't all that straight forward, but you need to tell me what results you can guarantee me, and I'll see if I want to take the risk. If that's worth it to try and get my sales up. So, what's your guarantee?</p></li>
</ol>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="/talk/t/quickmvp-and-digital-marketing/7596/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>/talk/t/quickmvp-and-digital-marketing/7596/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 01:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">talk.cregox.com-post-7596-1</guid>
        <source url="/talk/t/quickmvp-and-digital-marketing/7596.rss">Quickmvp and digital marketing</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
